Guide to the International Monitor Institute Records, 1986-2006 and undated RL.00604
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Organizational Records Series, 1986-2006, 43 boxes
  - Rwanda Archive Subseries, 1993-2001 and undated
    - Rwanda transcripts
      - Tape 141, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1993 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Mar. 11.
    - Rwanda tribunal commendation letters, 1998 Mar. 8 (Box OR33)
    - United Nations Security Council Resolution 955, 1994 (Box OR33)
    - War crimes, incitement to genocide (radio broadcasts), undated and 1999 (Box OR33)
  - Other Regions and Interregional Y1993-2002
    The majority of material in this subseries regards human rights abuses in Africa, including in Burundi, Ethopia/Eritrea, Uganda, Sierra Leone, Sudan, and in Latin American, especially in El Salvador. Other countries include Haiti, India, Chechnya, and Belarus. The subseries consists primarily of reports from, for example, Amnesty International, as well as general organizational and press records. "People" records include correspondence, press contacts and other figures involved in human rights projects, most prominently the South African Judge Richard Goldstone.
    - Africa (Box OR34)
      - "A Child's Nightmare: Burundi Children at Risk," field report by Marc Sommers, 1998 (Box OR34)
      - Côte d'Ivoire - Women's Commission, 1991-1993 (Box OR34)
      - "Never Kneel Down: Africa's Unfinished Revolution" (Eritrea), undated (Box OR34)
      - Ethiopa and Eritrea - Women's Commission, 1992 (Box OR34)
      - Report of the Accountability Review Boards - bombings of United States embassies in Nairobie and Dar es Salaam, undated (Box OR34)
      - "The Children's War: Towards Peace in Sierra Leone," 1997 Mar. 26 - Apr.16 (Box OR34)
      - Sierra Leone Archive - first quarter support, 1999 Oct.-Dec. (Box OR34)
      - Sierra Leone - documentary footage abstracts, undated (Box OR34)
      - Sierra Leone, general, 1999-2000 and undated (Box OR34)
      - "The Special Court for Sierra Leone: A General Plan for Justice and the Rule of Law," undated (Box OR34)
      - Sudan - general organizational and press records, 2001 (Box OR34)
      - Africa Rights Monitor, "The Stories We Must Tell: Ugandan Children and the Atrocities of the Lord's Resistance Army," 1998 (Box OR34)
      - Women's Commission - Kenya, Somalia and Southern Sudan, 1993 Mar. (Box OR34)
    - Latin America
      - Argentina rights suit, 1996 (Box OR34)
      - "Academic Freedom and University Autonomy in Chile," Michael Fleet, Latin American Studies Association, 1997 (Box OR34)
      - Columbia overview, undated (Box OR34)
      - America's Watch - El Salvador, 1992 Sep. and 1994 Mar. (Box OR34)
      - Developing national civilian police in El Salvador, 1992 (Box OR34)
      - "Human Rights, Development and Democracy: Experience of the United Nations in Post-Conflict El Salvador," 1993 Apr. 15 (Box OR34)
      - Human Rights Report on El Salvador, United States Department of State, 1992 (Box OR34)
      - La Prensa Grafica, El Conflicto En El Salvador, 1992 (Box OR34)
      - United Nations Observer Mission in El Salvador (ONUSAL), 1993 and undated (Box OR34)
        Documents are in Spanish.
      - "Organizacion de los Trabajos del Periodo de Sesiones," 1993-1994 (Box OR34)
      - "Report on UNDP Activities and Coordination Related to the Peace Process in El Salvador," 1993 Apr. 29 (Box OR34)
      - "Texto Subjeto A Embargo Hasta Las 11:00 AM Del Dia Lunes 15 De Marzo De 1993" (El Salvador) (Box OR35)
      - United Nations Security Council - El Salvador, reports, 1991-1994, 2 folders (Box OR35)
      - "UN-Sponsored Report Finds Death Squads Still Active in El Salvador" (El Salvador Policy Project), 1994 Aug. 11 (Box OR35)
      - Guatemala general organizational and press records, 1998-2001 (Box OR35)
      - Promotores de Paz, Revista Del Programa de Educacion Y Accion Para La Paz, Centrade Estudios Internacionales (CEI), 1996-1997 (Box OR35)
      - Women's Commission - Central America (Box OR35)
    - Eastern Europe, Haiti, Eastern Mediterranean, Central and South Asia
      - Human Rights Watch - Republic of Belarus violations of academic freedom, 1999 Jul. (Box OR35)
      - Chechnya, 1995, 2000 and undated (Box OR35)
      - Haitian women and reproductive healthcare documentaries, 1995 (Box OR35)
      - Amnesty International - India, "'An Unnatural Fate': 'Disappearances' and impunity in the Indian States of Jummu and Kashmir and Punjab," 1993 Dec. 15 (Box OR35)
      - India, general, 2000 and undated (Box OR35)
      - BBC transcript of "The Accused" (Israeli in Beirut), 2001 June 17 (Box OR35)
      - Uzbekistan - general organizational and press records, 2001 (Box OR35)
    - People (Box OR36)
      - Albright, Madeleine, portrait, undated (Box OR36)
      - Arbour, Judge Louise (Yugoslavia and Rwanda), 1996-1999 (Box OR36)
      - Atyam, Angelina Acheng - nomination for United Nations Prize in the Field of Human Rights, 1998 Aug. 13 (Box OR36)
      - Brumley, Brian, Associated Press regarding Cambodia and Rwanda Archives, 1995-1997 and undated (Box OR36)
      - Friedrich, Ebert and Stiftung, 1996-1997 (Box OR36)
      - Goldstone, Richard, 1992-1996 (Box OR36)
      - Judge Goldstone footage (Johannesburg and Yugoslavia), undated (Box OR36)
      - Kamper, Teunis (Rwanda and Yugoslavia), 1996-1997 (Box OR36)
      - Marks, Laura - curriculum vitae, International Rescue Committee (IRC)newsletter, IRC and Unocal, proposal regarding Sierra Leone, proposal regarding Liberia, 1999 (Box OR36)
      - Rich, Bryan, freelance reporter, 2002 (Box OR36)
      - Simmons, David, 2000 June 6 (Box OR36)
      - Stapelton, Barbara, BBC, 1998 (Box OR36)
      - Sugarman, Martin, 1999 (Box OR36)
  - General Office Files Subseries, 1991-2006 and undated
    This subseries includes broadcast logs regarding the status of human rights abuses in various regions, particularly in the Balkans and Rwanda, legal documents such as license agreement contracts and information exchange agreements with organizations such as Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch, or production companies including Linden Productions. Internal organizational records include project summaries and proposals, information regarding funding opportunities, correspondence regarding acquisition of materials, and IMI organizational summaries and brochures and web-design. Documentary projects and scripts, material on video projects such as Berserkistan and Hotspots, and material on child soldiers in various conflicts comprise other noteable material. Included in this subseries but not included in the subseries date span are documents regarding Nuremberg war crimes tribunal from 1945-1946.
    - ABC news broadcast logs - bulk Bosnia, 1993 Apr. 8-29 (Box OR37)
      Full-text.
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1993 Apr. 18-May 30 (Box OR37)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1993 Apr. 30-Aug. 22 (Box OR37)
    - ABC broadcast logs, 1993 June 1-Sep. 30 (Box OR37)
    - ABC/Sky News broadcast logs, 1993 Aug. 23-Dec. 28 (Box OR37)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1993 Oct. 1-Dec. 28 (Box OR37)
    - ABC News printout, 1993 Apr.-Dec., 1 of 3 (Box OR37)
    - ABC News printout, 1993 Apr.-Dec., 2-3 of 3 folders (Box OR38)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1994 Jan. 2-June 12 (Box OR38)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1994 Jan 2.-Apr. 1 (Box OR38)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1994 Apr. 11-June 12 (Box OR38)
    - ABC News broadcast logs, 1994 Apr. 2-June 12 (Box OR38)
    - Agreements/contracts, 1998-2002 (Box OR39)
    - Amnesty International - Image Archives, 2000 and undated (Box OR39)
    - Amnesty International License Agreement, 1998 (Box OR39)
    - Archive's showreel, 1997-1999 (Box OR39)
    - Army Pictorial Center footage catalogue - War Crimes Trials, Nuremberg, 1945-1946 (Box OR39)
    - Articles, miscellaneous, 1999-2000 (Box OR39)
    - Associated Press Television News (APTN), correspondence regarding archival material on child soldiers, 1996-1999 (Box OR39)
    - APTN Library search, 1999 Mar. 9 (Box OR39)
    - Audiovisual Promotion Distribution Unit, 1997-1999 (Box OR39)
    - Berserkistan, Pacific Interactive Media and Reuters Television, undated (Box OR39)
    - Bibliography of sources on Cambodia, El Salvador, and Mozambique, undated (Box OR39)
    - Book inventory, 2000 June 26 (Box OR39)
    - Borderline Video, 1997 May 22 (Box OR39)
    - Capa Television Documentaries, 2006 and undated (Box OR39)
    - Child soldiers, 1998-1999 and undated (Box OR39)
    - Cineplex Odeon Group correspondence, 1996 Oct. 15 (Box OR39)
    - Computer hardware orders and receipts, 1999 (Box OR39)
    - Contacts, undated (Box OR39)
    - Correspondence, general, 1994-2002 (Box OR39)
    - Correspondence with David Hoffman regarding agreement, 1997 (Box OR39)
    - Creative Edge Enterprises (website design), 2001-2002 (Box OR39)
    - Crimes of war, 1999 (Box OR39)
    - Film finding priorities, undated (Box OR39)
    - Film guide, undated (Box OR39)
    - General human rights, 1996 (Box OR39)
    - Grants, 2002 (Box OR40)
    - Guillermo Kuitca - exhibition press release, 1999 (Box OR40)
    - Hotspots pilot, 1999 (Box OR40)
    - Human rights timelines, undated (Box OR40)
    - Human Rights Watch correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box OR40)
    - Human Rights Watch main film, 2001 (Box OR40)
    - Human Rights Watch - Wyle, Noah, 2001 (Box OR40)
    - Human Rights Watch videos for annual dinner, 2000 (Box OR40)
    - Information Exchange Agreements, 2001 (Box OR40)
    - International Criminal Court - Bosnia and Rwanda, 1996-1997 and undated (Box OR40)
    - International Documentary Association (IDA) Fiscal Sponsorship information package, 2002 (Box OR40)
    - International Institute of Higher Studies in Criminal Sciences pamphlet, 1994 (Box OR40)
    - International Monitor Institute activities, 1995 and undated (Box OR40)
    - International Monitor Institute archive summaries and drafts, 1996 Nov. 26 (Box OR40)
    - International Monitor Institute brochures, 1993-2000 and undated (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute - digital, general, 1993-1997 (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute documentary, 1997 (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute general, 1995-1996 and undated (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute organization summaries, 1997 and undated (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute profit and loss by class, 1999 Oct. 1 - 2000 June 19 (Box OR41)
    - International Monitor Institute staff policty definition, 1998 Jul. (Box OR41)
    - Independent Television News (ITN) archive search, 1999 Mar. 9 (Box OR41)
    - Interview prospectives, 2001 (Box OR41)
    - Itineraries, 1996 (Box OR41)
    - Kurt Schwitters archive at the Sprengel Museum Hannover, 1999 (Box OR41)
    - Letters regarding acquisition of documentary tapes, 1994 (Box OR41)
    - Letter - request for support for child soldiers project, 1999 Aug. 30 (Box OR41)
    - Linden biographies, undated (Box OR41)
    - Linden Productions agreement for cost and licensing rights to child soldier project, 1999 Jul. 2 (Box OR41)
    - Linden Productions archive sample packet, undated (Box OR41)
    - Linden Productions exhibit, undated (Box OR41)
    - Linden Productions and International Human Rights Law Institute (IHRLI) Agreement, 1993-1994 (Box OR41)
    - "Licensing Footage: Copyright and Other Legal Considerations," by Philip Meyer, undated (Box OR41)
    - "Living with Genocide," by Stephen Wissman, undated (Box OR41)
    - The Macarthur Foundation (mostly regarding Balkan Archives), 1995-1998 (Box OR41)
    - Media, general, 2006 (Box OR41)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995-2002 (Box OR41)
    - Museum of Tolerance, undated (Box OR41)
    - National Archives, 1997 (Box OR42)
    - News World 99, 5th Forum for the News Industry, 1999 Nov. 3-5 (Box OR42)
    - Nexis/Lexis service, undated (Box OR42)
    - "Notes on the Use of Video Tape as Information and Evidence," by Tom Warrick, undated (Box OR42)
    - Nuremberg, undated (Box OR42)
    - Original International Monitor Institute database building instructions, undated (Box OR42)
    - Phone lists, 1993-1996 (Box OR42)
    - Physicians for Human Rights - violations of medical neutrality, 1993-1994 (Box OR42)
    - Proposal for collaboration between Witness and International Monitor Institute, undated (Box OR42)
    - Proposal for the creation of a videotape/photographic computer database and archive, 1993 Jul. (Box OR42)
    - Proposal for general support of the International Monitor Institute, undated (Box OR42)
    - A proposal to use the internet for peacekeeping, HOPE institute, Keith Spicer, 1998 (Box OR42)
    - Real Impact request for services, 2001-2002 (Box OR42)
    - The Reckoning Grant, 1996 Jul. 12 (Box OR42)
    - The Simon Wiesenthal/Museum of Tolerance proposal, "The Friedl Dicker-Brandeis Project," undated (Box OR42)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center, 1998 (Box OR42)
    - "Spielberg's List: Survivors of the Shoah," by Paul Donovan, on digital video, undated (Box OR42)
    - Statement by Justice Arbour, Prosectuor of the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia and Rwanda, 1999 Mar. 31 (Box OR42)
    - Testimony video breakdown, undated (Box OR42)
    - Transcript of conference call with Ham Fish regarding archive development, 1997 Apr. 28 (Box OR42)
    - Trip log - London, 2002 Feb. 26 - 2002 Mar. 4 (Box OR42)
    - United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees shot list, photo captions and credits, 1991-1998 (Box OR42)
    - United States Department of State, 1996-1997 (Box OR42)
    - Vincent Mcgee letter regarding funding, 1997 Jul. 22 (Box OR42)
    - "Voices" scripts (including floppy), undated (Box OR42)
    - "Voices" shot list, 1993 (Box OR42)
    - War Crimes trials - Nuremberg, Germany - transcript, 1945-1949 (Box OR43)
    - Warren Buffet correspondence, 1991 (Box OR43)
    - Web projects, 1998-1999 and undated (Box OR43)
    - Website projects, 2001 and undated (Box OR43)
    - International Monitor Institute website, 1998-2002 (Box OR43)
    - Website with templates, 2000 (Box OR43)
    - "Where are they now?" 2001 (Box OR43)
    - White House correspondence regarding Scott recommendation of Dave Scheffer, 1997 (Box OR43)
    - WITNESS organizational summary update, 2001 Jul. (Box OR43)
    - Women's Commission for Refugee Women and Children, 1992-1994 and undated (Box OR43)
    - Women's Commission tape descriptions, 1999 (Box OR43)
    - The Youngest Warriors, including diskette, 1999-2000 (Box OR43)
- Oversize Material Series, 1998-2000 and undated, 1 oversize folder
  Contains maps and posters collected by IMI pertaining to human rights hotspots.
  - Night vision photograph, Sarajevo, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Map, Kosovo, circa 1998 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - "Ethnic Map, Republic of Croatia and Republic of Bosnia and Hercegovina", The Miroslav Krleẑa Lexicographical Institute, Zagreb, Croatia, undated. (Oversize-folder 1)
  - "Iraq Crimes Against Humanity", DI Design Center/MPG 378012AI 3-01, c. 2000 (Oversize-folder 1)